warm welcome to icici lombard general
insurance company limited
q3 a nine month fy 21 earnings
conference call
from the senior management we have with
us today mr bhargav das gupta
md and ceo of the company mr gopal
balachandran
cfo and cro mr sanjeev
mantri executive director retail
and mr alok agarwal executive director
wholesale
as a reminder all participant clients
will be in the listen only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes
should you need assistance during the
call please signal an operator by
pressing star
then zero on your touchstone phone
please note that this conference is
being recorded
i now have the conference over to mr
bharg of dasgupta
md and ceo icici lombard general
insurance limited
thank you and over to you sir
thank you and good afternoon good
evening to each one of you
thank you for joining the earnings
conference call of isis lombard
for q3 2021 and for nine month 2021
i hope all of you and your colleagues
are staying safe and healthy
so what i'll do is i'll give a brief
overview of the industry trends
and developments that we've witnessed uh
in the you know our past few months
post this our cfo gopala children will
share the financial performance of the
company for the quarter and nine months
ended december 31
2020.
the growth tragically seen in the
economy since the second quarter of 2021
has picked up in this quarter
uh the high frequency indicators like
automobile sales
railway freight traffic growth in
non-oil and non-gold imports seen during
third quarter shows
hopeful sign that of a sharper recovery
than what we
anticipate at the beginning of the year
in fact some of the worst hit sectors
such as
hospitality and travel have also seen
some pick up in the third quarter
and the introduction of the vaccine is
expected to catalyze
economic activities further which can
provide tailwinds
for india's economic growth now in this
context
the general insurance industry has been
a safe harbor even through the times
of uncertainty with gross direct premium
income
back in the black segments such as the
motor insurance
saw encouraging performance during this
quarter driven by growing need for
personal
mobility and spillover demand from the
festive seasons
the pent up demand for healthy insurance
seen in the first half
has shown some signs of tapering
as far as commercial lines are concerned
the fire segment continued to show
rovers growth aided by the rate hike
that came into force in january 2020
while marine and engineering lines
witnessed some pickup with the
resumption of
economic activity in this quarter with
the current macro and micro
indicators indicators come into play we
remain confident that the gi
industry is set to outperform that in
terms of growth
now speaking of the performance as per
the disclosure on the website of rdi the
general insurance
industry registered a growth of point
five percent for nine month
uh 2021 over the previous nine months
uh with the industry gdpr moving up to
uh one uh one four five six point seven
nine billion
uh in nine month range 21 142 0.85
billion rupees in nine month 2022 2020.
the combined ratio for the industry was
105.2 in the first half of 2021 as
compared to 115.7
in the first half of 2020 based on
available information from public
disclosures
excluding one company which has not
disclosed its numbers for q2 fi 2021 as
yet
further the overall combined ratio for
the private multi-line general insurance
was
insurance was 103.0 in h1 2021
as compared to 107.2 in h1 2020.
now since our halfway results call we
have witnessed new regular announcements
that are focused on policyholders
benefit including the exposure draft
with standard terms and conditions
issued by the authority
in order to make available standard
travel insurance personal
accident and named indemnity-based
vector bond products
with common coverage and policy wordings
across the industry
the authority also issued guidelines on
certain standard products that shall be
mandatory
offered by generation insurers carrying
out fire and allied perils insurance
business with effect from first
april 2020. the standard products
include
bharat grihar raksha meant for home
building and home content
bharat sukhmaodiyam suraksha meant for
enterprise with total value at risk up
to
rupees five crores and bharat jam
suraksha meant for enterprises
with total value at risk from 5 close to
25 quarters
the authority had also issued an
exposure draft on withdrawal of existing
long-term credit link group insurance
products under the health insurance
business
with effect from january 1 2021 the
industry through the gi council had
represent has represented the industry
let me now turn to the claims behavior
observed in the recent quarters
with the economic activity normalizing
post motor road claim
you know normalizing motor od claim
frequency has reached previous levels
in case of health overall claim
frequency has almost reached peak orbit
levels
for the industry covered claims claims
reported as on december 31 2020 was
roughly about 7.68 lakhs of its 39 000
claims were reported with
isis lombard however the new covet cases
reported in the month of december has
seen slight moderation
the recent pandemic provided us an
opportunity to foster an absolute
innovation
deliver improved customer service
upskilling and reskinning of our
employees and distributors
over 97.5 policies 97.5
we should buy us in the nine month ended
december 2020 where our import paper is
formed
under the sme segment close to 91
percent of business sourced were through
these digital solutions
during the quarter we also launched a
website dedicated for our
small and medium businesses the new
platform will serve as a one-stop
solution for sme owners to buy
or renew insurance products endorse
their insurance policies and register
claims
this is first in the industry in our
previous call we also
shared about our new technology uh
technology and
enabled enablements including the ai and
ml solutions
that help in policy issuance claims and
fraud control and servicing
our automated ai solution auto you know
auto approved close to uh 66 percent of
motor braking in cell sense elections in
december 2020
up from 40.6 in march 2020. on the
health insurance front
under group health policies 63.1 percent
of the fresh cashless requests
were authorized by an aiml enabled
engine for december 2020
as compared to 31 in march uh 2020.
our mobile app uh i'll take care has
crossed 3.44 lakh downloads
enabling more and more customers to
avail our insurance and wellness
solutions
we continue to add digital capabilities
and servicing including the process of
endorsements
since its launch last year 73 of all
group health
premium bearing endorsements are now
done digitally
reducing processing time from weeks to
minutes and
roughly about 45 percent of our motor
policy endorsements from
agency channel are processed real time
using our digital solutions
we've also in introduce a revised hr
policy where wherein
employees can work from anywhere even
post the pandemic while ensuring work
environment we create is comfortable and
secure
now through this young unprecedented
laser focus has been on enhancing
customer experience
new product offerings creating workplace
transformation thereby adding value to
our stakeholders
we are continually focusing on in
evolving our strategies to further
consolidate our position in general
engine segment
while retaining our mission of creating
long-term values for our
stakeholders through prudent risk
selection and sustained profitability
i will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently
concluded quarter thanks bhagav and uh
good evening to each one of you i will
now give you a brief overview of the
financial performance of the company for
quarter three this year and nine months
this year
we have put up the results presentation
on our website you can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
the gross direct premium income of the
company stood at rupees 105.25 billion
in nine months
fy21 as compared to 101.32 billion in
nine months last year
a growth of three point nine percent
compared to industry growth of two point
five percent
for a similar period on a quarterly
basis the gdp grew in quarter three by
nine point two percent
over quarter three last year compared to
the industry growth of 4.9 percent
our focus on preferred segments
primarily draw our gdpi growth
consequent to the increase in minimum
prescribed rates for certain occupancies
under the fire segment
this portfolio registered a robust gdpa
growth of 44.8 percent in nine months fi
thereby catalyzing the gdpi growth of
our property and casualty segment
going forward the growth in this segment
is expected to normalize
as indicated in our results presentation
the overall property and casualty
segment
grew by 22 percent for nine months fi 21
over nine months fi 2020
on the retail side of the business motor
segment was back in the black
registering a growth of two point one
percent in nine months fi 21
individual health integrity business
grew by twenty five point seven percent
for nine month fy 2021.
to harness the potential of these
segments we have been expanding our
distribution network
to increase penetration in tire 3 and
tire 4 cities
our agents including the point of sale
distribution or poss
increased to 55 615 as on december 31
up from 52 785 as on september 30 2020.
the advanced premium numbers was rupees
31.97 billion
as at december 31 2020 from
31.60 billion as at september 30 2020.
in so far as the progress in relation to
the scheme of arrangement with
barclayexa is concerned
we have filed the application with nclt
and nclt has directed us to convene a
meeting of shareholders
to consider and approve the scheme of
arrangement on february 23 2021
the expenses incurred of about 0.36
billion
have been absorbed in the p l during
nine months fi 2021.
our combined ratio stood at 99.1 percent
in nine months fi 2021 compared to
hundred point five percent in nine
months fbi 2020
despite the cyclone and flood losses
excluding the impact of cyclone and
flood losses the combined ratio stood at
97.7 percent in
nine months fi 2021 as against 99.5
percent in nine months fy 2020
combined ratio for the quarter three
stood at 97.9 percent
compared to 98.7 percent in quarter
three last year
excluding the impact of cyclone and
floods for the quarter three the
combined ratio stood at 96.6 percent in
this quarter
as against 98.7 percent in quarter three
fy 2020
our investment assets rose to 298.92
billion at december 31 2020
as compared to 291.62 billion at
september 30 2020.
our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 4.05 times at december 31
2020 as
point compared to times at september
thirty twenty twenty
investment income increased to sixteen
point five nine billion in nine months
five twenty one
as compared to fourteen point four one
billion in nine months fy 2020
on a quarterly basis investment income
increased to five point six eight
billion rupees in quarter three five
twenty one
as compared to four point two seven
billion in quarter three five twenty
twenty
within this our capital gains was at
rupees two point nine two billion in
nine months five twenty one
as compared to 2.24 billions in nine
months fy 2020.
capital gains for quarter three five
twenty one was at rupees one point zero
eight billion
as compared to rupees point one seven
billion in quarter three five twenty
twenty
our profit before track grew by thirteen
point four percent to rupees fifteen
point zero four billion in nine months
five twenty one
as compared to rupees thirteen point two
six billion in nine months five twenty
twenty
whereas profit before tax grew by seven
point three percent to four point
eight billion in quarter three five 21
as compared to rupees three point nine
zero billion in quarter three five
twenty
this includes upfront expensing of
acquisition cost
relative to the growth of nine point two
percent in gdpr for quarter three five
twenty twenty twenty
one whereas the full benefit of the
earned premium will be realized over the
policy period consequently profit after
tax grew by twenty three point six
percent to rupees eleven point two seven
billion in nine months fi twenty one
as compared to rupees nine point one two
billion in nine months fy 2020
primarily due to lower effective tax
rate of 25 percent
profit after tax grew by six point six
percent up to three point one four
billion in quarter three five twenty one
as compared to rupees two point four
billion in quarter three up by 2020.
written on average equity was 22.4
percent in nine months five twenty one
as compared to twenty one point eight
percent in nine months five twenty
the return on average equity for quarter
three five twenty one was seventeen
point six percent as compared to twenty
point three percent in quarter three fi
twenty twenty
this includes the up front expensing
acquisition cost which i referred to
earlier
relative to the growth of nine point two
percent gdp for quarter three five
twenty twenty one
whereas the full benefit of earned
premium will be realized over the policy
period
solvency ratio was 2.76 times at
december 31 2020
as against 2.74 times at september 30
continued to be higher than the minimum
regulatory requirement of 1.5
as i conclude i would like to reiterate
that we ended quarter three and nine
months with healthy financials
our competitive strengths which
contribute to sustainability
and positions as well for future growth
includes consistency market leadership
diversified product mix with
multi-channel distribution network
excellence in customer service and
technology robust risk selection
and strong investment returns on
diversified portfolio
through our business performance we have
always endeavored to create long-term
sustainable value for all our
stakeholders
i would like to thank you all for
attending this earnings conference call
and would be happy to take questions
that you may have thank you
thank you very much we will now begin
the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on the touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
questioning q you may press star and two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
to ask questions please press star and
one
the first question is from the line of
vitish gulati from high tongue please go
ahead
yes sir thank you for giving me an
opportunity so my question is related to
the benefit policies that you spoke
about so can you just update us on what
is the latest
regarding what irda is saying regarding
these policies which are attached along
with
their loan products and also if you
could help us with how much of benefit
versus indemnity we have done in q3
and what has been the claim ratio of the
two categories
uh so let me uh answer the first part of
the question
and i'll ask gopal to explain the
overall
you know numbers on the benefit side uh
this quarter vis-a-vis
uh q3 of uh last year so in terms of uh
the circular the circular had the given
uh you know it was an exposure it was a
you know
kind of an exposure draft which said
that from first january onwards
these policies will be stopped uh as an
industry we
uh obviously represented you know this
would have
we believe uh you know negative impact
so we represented
uh as of now we've not heard anything
either way
uh but the fact is that the uh draft uh
uh you know policy hasn't been converted
into a final uh
regulation effective first january so uh
as of now it's not been withdrawn
that is the status uh when we finally
get a confirmation we can give you the
uh final picture from the regulatory
perspective
uh one of the things that has happened
for us in icc lombard is that a large
part of our benefit
uh you know health benefit policies is
uh comes through bank issue and channel
in any case and within that uh from icsa
bank
and uh you know separate from this
circular
icc bank had anyway decided you know
sometime in
early this quarter that they would
you know reduce the focus of
distribution of health insurance
you know business particularly in the
attachment side because they are
focusing on
building out the core banking business
uh given that
you know the first half it was low and
you know the opportunities are high
they wanted the team to focus on code
banking business uh
the bank has indicated that it would
obviously re-assess this approach
in due course uh but because of that
call of the bank anyways
you know whether the circuit is
effective or not as of now our benefit
business has come
down significantly and if you look at
our aggregate health numbers
that's one of the reasons why we've been
impacted adversely
but specific details about numbers i'll
ask gopal to give you
yeah i'll give you the numbers for
the retail segment because that's what
would be of
importance if you look at the breakup of
the retail
business that we do the indemnity
business that we did in nine months last
year was about 531 crores
this year nine months that number is
about 644 crores a growth of about 21.3
in so far as the benefit is concerned
the same numbers for
nine months last year was about 638
crores
that number for the nine months this
year is about 287 crores
and to your other point with respect to
what are the loss ratios that we get to
see
in so far as indemnity
is concerned is the last year again nine
months the individual loss ratios was
roughly at about 70 percent
this year uh nine months the uh
indemnity loss ratios it was operating
at about 83 percent
generally it has been a profitable
segment the loss ratios kind of ranges
anywhere between
i would say uh close to 40 35 to 50
percent
depending on the experience that we see
between periods
actually the reason is masking is
because over the last three years the
combined ratio and health has been very
strong at around 90 percent so now that
we are doing less of benefit policies uh
and also
even if you look at the nine month
numbers our health insurance claim ratio
or combined ratio is also looking
is expected to go high will that be the
trend going forward
i think so far as the trend is concerned
i think what we have
what we have explained even in our prior
calls
uh in so far as the nature of the
indemnity business is concerned
again when you split split the now i'm
talking about indemnity in the aggregate
when you look at the corporate part of
the business inherently they come with a
very high
loss ratio but the cost of acquisition
for that portfolio is relative in a
single digit number
and in so far as the retail portfolio is
concerned
the loss ratio tends to kind of be
relatively lower
however the cost of acquisition tends to
be higher but
both the portfolios put together i think
the attempt for us has been to try and
run
the overall combined ratio at the
threshold level of about
100 that we have spoken about in so far
as the way forward is concerned i think
the attempt will be to exactly
uh continue to do that in so far as this
particular period is concerned as i said
obviously there has been an impact in so
far as the growth in the benefit segment
is concerned
but however in so far as the way forward
is concerned i think we would logically
expect some of this
benefit growth to play through and the
overall
health loss ratios is something as i
said all the combination is something
that we would expect to maintain at the
threshold of
100 that's one the second aspect is what
i spoke about also with respect to
let's say covet claims uh what we have
seen of course clearly
that all of us can see is the
incremental number of intimation seems
to be on the decline
which is quite evident and even we have
kind of seen that particular experience
obviously one will have to wait and see
how the developments takes place so far
as quarter four is concerned if the
current trend continues then obviously
to that extent
the experience on the loss ratio should
get better so far as covid claims are
concerned
but at the same time on the non-covet
cases if you recollect
in terms of what we have been speaking
over the last few quarters
whenever logically we would expect a
reduction in
uh covet cases the non-covet cases will
start to come back and in quarter three
specific
we have already started to see the claim
intimations coming back to
uh in fact uh slightly higher than even
pre-covet times
so hence a mix of both the attempt will
be to answer your point i think
the attempt will be on an overall health
portfolio we would want to kind of run
the book at a combined issue of around
100 percent
thank you that's it
thank you before we take the next
question
we'd like to inform participants that in
order that the management is able to
address questions from all participants
in the conference
please limit your questions to two per
participant
should you have a follow-up question we
request you to rejoin the queue
we take the next question from the line
of age of frederick from bnk securities
please go ahead uh thanks for the
opportunity
so my question is with respect to motor
uh underwriting loss ratios
so uh sorry underwriting uh quantum
uh so that was pretty
worse versus last uh req
however the loss ratios are much better
so
does this imply that we are upfronting
our question costs and therefore the
underwriting
uh profit is showing such a big negative
number or has there been any change to
the commission structure
uh that that's my first question second
is with respect to
the change in ibnr as a proportion of
total claims that has been pretty low
numbered this quarter again this is
because of the conservative assumption
we have done earlier
so those are my two questions so again
i'll ask
gopal to answer the second one let me
answer the first one um
so if you if you remember one of the
things that we had said at the beginning
of the year was
or after the first quarter we had seen
some benefit in terms of frequency
reductions
on the motor side but we had said that
it would be improved to take the full
benefit in the first quarter
because there would be you know increase
in frequency as
people come back and personal mobility
picks up and we
would prefer to even it out for the year
uh so that's a call that we took and i
think in hindsight that's
it was a conservative call and in
hindsight that was the right call
so when you look at the loss ratio you
have to keep that in mind uh in terms of
what's happening
uh you know and so i would rather you
know so look at an annual basis rather
than just on quarterly basis
the second point is what you're saying
is absolutely right so
the basic accounting you know policy
that we have in general insurance is
that
the so we don't have back as in the
sourcing cost is not
uh different over the period of the
you know policy it is upfront so
whenever
in a quarter we have a high growth
relative to the prior quarters
because the income or the earning of the
policies that were written in the prior
quarter comes in now but the premium
that we write
is again spread over the next 12 months
but the sourcing cost if it is
significantly
uh as in the percentage of if the growth
is very high
then the upfront cost becomes uh you
know comes and impacts it in that
quarter
a bit like what happens in strain for
life business with a shorter duration
so that happens so if you see this
quarter our motor growth was
roughly about uh you know about 14 14.3
percent
but if you go back to our motor growth
in q1 was about 22 percent
minus uh and you know for the whole year
a half year
also it was negative uh six and a half
percent so we have seen
tremendous growth uh in this quarter
relative to what we saw in the previous
quarter
so that has had the impact that you've
undefined uh on the ib yeah on the
second point ajax i just want to kind of
get clarity are you referring to with
the context of motor are you
or are you referring in the context of
overall
over ulcer overall so overall obviously
i think there it will obviously
and overall you are looking at ibnr as a
percentage of
total camps total claims obviously so
yeah so i think obviously what happens
uh
ajax is uh obviously ibinars are
based on estimations of losses that we
expect on the
various segments of businesses and to
that to the extent
uh some of the portfolio claims are
actualized
then obviously a large part of this
claims will get reduced from
ibnr and logically kind of get converted
as a part of either claims paid or to
that extent it will be a part of
claims outstanding assuming if any of
them are yet to be settled
uh so that's one the second factor is in
this particular
quarter i think what has also happened
is in line with what we had mentioned
even in the earlier quarters
some of the outstanding uh crop
receivables
the receipt of which had happened in
quarter one and quarter two
uh there has been outflow of claims
which has happened in quarter three so
hence to that extent also there is an
element of
both claims outstanding as well as let's
say to the extent of the ibinar that
would have carried on the
crop portfolio that would have
significantly seen a decrease
and the third factor is in so far as the
approach to reserving is concerned
there has been no change in the
reserving approach
vis-a-vis quarter three as compared to
any of the prior periods the approach
has pretty much remained the same and in
fact
when you look at the loss ratios uh
specifically in the context of uh
a motor for example you would have seen
for in
for example on own damage for quarter
three the loss ratios were
were actually at almost about 63 percent
visibly let's say almost 59 percent that
you had seen in quarter two
or for the matter of fact even third
party quarter three loss ratios are
about 65 percent as compared to
uh let's say the uh tp loss ratio of
about 62 in quarter two
so hence from an approach or a
methodology there is being no change it
is just that
some of those ibn reserves that would
have been created in the earlier periods
they would have got actualized in terms
of
uh claims getting reported and paid
yeah that is very helpful sir thank you
thanks a lot for your time
thank you the next question is from the
line of ud karivala
from ambet capital please go ahead
am i audible sir yeah yeah
uh thank you for the opportunity my
question was um on account of the
uh in relation to the investment
leverage
uh now this is i guess uh in this
quarter it has come down
uh to 4.05 so you could
some color around this uh what do you
expect going forward
and and some rational behind this tip
yeah so two major factors one is as
gopal explained there was
some of the older policies in crop that
we had written i mean you know as you
know money comes in much later
so premium had come in uh in the earlier
part of the year
and the payout of claims happened this
quarter so there was a large amount that
went out
that was one secondly uh even in terms
of
the leverage uh you know for uh you know
last year i think for the year
gone by and even for halfway leave we've
not paid any interim dividend
uh because of the regulatory uh uh
you know mandate that we've got that
none of no no insurance company or no
bank is allowed to pay
a dividend so effectively normally we
would have paid out some dividends
that would have reduced the denominator
but also we had the impact of the crop
claims being paid out uh
in one shot so but for this the number
would have been uh
you know in the you know 4.11 or 4.13
depending on what number you look at
in that ballpark so so if i have
understood you correct you're saying
that because the dividends were not paid
your denominator
uh as in the path was the earnings was
inflated
and and and and your numerator took a
hit because of the outflow on account of
the crossfire
yeah and these are the problems in the
context of
uh relative comparison with the nine
months of previous period i think
vargo's
response is in that context yeah and
what crop outflows are these when word
is
so these are crop portfolios udit that
we have written during the year 2018
uh some of which were outstanding with
respect to uh
collectibility of premiums and during
this year which is 2021
as i explained in quarter one and
quarter two we were able to realize a
large part of those outstanding premiums
for the crop business that we had
underwritten in 2018 2019
and in quarter two and quarter three
quarter three largely is where we have
been able we have been
uh we have had a share of outflow with
respect to settlement of those claims
okay and just one last week related to
this do you incrementally
i related to crop is there any large
outfit still remaining or
most of it is now our outstanding
premiums is virtually as good as
uh zero but for a very small amount of a
business that we're of roughly about 77
crores
is all that remains on the balance sheet
but otherwise all other
crop premiums that were outstanding as
as at the earlier balance sheets they
have all been received
thank you thank you so much
thank you the next question is from the
line of fresh chain from yes securities
please go ahead yeah uh thank you sir
of course there's a very basic question
on the nap
to your nwp network ratio
that seems to have declined
substantially in this quarter
so what's the reason for that
you want to explain the accounting so
any p2 nwp
is purely a function of what kind of
business that you write
and hence to that extent i think
whatever
uh earnings that you would uh whatever
businesses that you were underwritten i
think they all get on a one by three
sixty five day basis
okay and to that extent i think it is
purely a function of uh
the volume of premiums that you have
underwritten but more importantly i
think when you look at
uh quarter three specific i am not
necessarily referring to let's say
the nap to nwp and wp ratio in fact
when you look at the nwp growth numbers
particularly for quarter three
you would see that the growth is almost
about 20 percent yeah
so that was the point that i was kind of
referring to now what effectively
happens is whenever you ride the
businesses
let's say the businesses are growing and
then what effectively happens is the
cost comes and hits you
upfront whereas this nwp growth of 20
is something that will start to get
earned
over the policy period and in the past
periods
relatively if you see the nwp growth for
let's say quarter one and quarter two
more specifically quarter one as
compared to quarter two the growth in
nwp has been relatively lower because of
understandably so the volumes of
business were also not so great
and then incremental earned premium
contributions
would be lower but as businesses have
started to pick up
in terms of growth logically you will
start to see the nap to nwp ratio is
going up
okay so going ahead ideally this should
start moving higher
is that the right way to think that is
correct i think
in terms of how we given the fact that
now a lot of activities have started to
open up
in the context of whether it is the
commercial activities commercial lines
of businesses
and motor in specific again uh as
bargain explained we have been able to
have
a significant out performance in so far
as growth is concerned
and even on the health part of the
business while it has been a mixed bag
in terms of growth as we speak but
logically at least so far as the way
forward is concerned definitely in terms
of opportunity one sees a lot of
positivity connect
and hence assuming things starts to get
much better than what we have seen over
the last nine months
definitely the nap to nwp ratio will
uh definitely look positive okay uh my
second question was on the
claims bit or the severity of the health
portfolio especially on the retail side
and frequently we mentioned that the
number of planes is
back to pre-covered levels but with
regards to severity
how how is that standing out and even
for the sales for the same thing on the
motor
motor od side do you think that the q4
could be really
uh you know bad as or really relatively
worse
competitively so in terms of the health
claims uh
you know what gopal explained is the
numbers have come back but
it's also on a larger base of policy so
if you look at our
uh non-covet frequency it's still
slightly lower than
uh you know what it was pre-pandemic
but it's kind of caught up mostly and
within that when we look at different
types of claims
we see the small medical management you
know this is medical management are
basically
uh let's say you have you have a stomach
you
go to the hospital for two days and come
back or you know just a you know it's a
fever
you can hospitalize for a couple of days
not surgery or not
uh you know an accidental you know
hospitalization etc
so those cases we've seen a lower
frequency still which is
similar trend what we've seen in the
past in terms of people
not going to hospitals you know unless
they really have to
so we've seen that frequency still
remain low uh
what that does is while the frequency
comes down the
you know the surgery cases are more
expensive so to that extent
the acl goes up uh for as a blend as a
mix
but if i look at each of those
categories as in the you know
aces or average claims has increased for
medical management cases or
elective surgery cases or uh you know or
an emergency case uh there the acs
hasn't gone up
significantly it's you know normal
inflation nothing particularly high
cobit claims uh you know gopal anyway
has given the numbers
that's coming down another motorcycle
motorcycle it's on on iron part there's
no
unusual spike in the acs
and also this we have reserved this
quarter four
uh sequentially as bhargavad mentioned
we have seen
uh improvement uh in the season actually
the
quarter encoder goes both on private
killer private car and two wheeler on cm
number has been very reasonable we do
believe that
waterfall or an overall from a growth
perspective should remain positive
okay thank you so much thank you
thank you the next question is from the
line of sanket goda from spark capital
please go ahead yeah
thanks thanks for the opportunity uh
my question is again on the benefit
based health products which which is one
of the major reason why we have a very
strong profitability and health
portfolio
so so just wanted to understand if icc
bank is going to become
zero almost on incremental basis if they
continue to focus on
core banking products assuming that in
attachment based
benefit based is allowed by a regulator
then then
uh then can it should be assumed that uh
given
the bank might be contributing bulk 80
or 90 percent of the benefit base what
would be doing
then again next year we could be seeing
a significant fall in this business
or or do you think this could be
substituted by sdc bank or access bank
when bhartiya exam will come in
probably in fy22 so that is my first
question on benefit based health
second second question which i had it
was with respect to moto tp
uh since since uh since uh actually uh
people
running on vehicles have significantly
gone up probably in 3q
compared to second quarter still still
the loss ratios what we are reporting in
moto 2p
at 65.5 uh or or 65.7 in third quarter
uh are these numbers sustainable given
given given historically we always had a
higher number
and and this lower number is largely
because lower claim information uh which
which which actually is looking at
and therefore he is providing lower or
or is it is it generally because of a
reserve release
from the past revealing which is leading
to this improvement
these are the two major questions one
small one which i have is with respect
to retail intensity
seems to be new retail internality seems
to be how slowed down sharply in third
quarter
at around 17 percent growth versus also
77 percent in q1 and 48
raised in q2 so if i just wanted to
understand the
broader trends there too yeah so the
three questions
so let me try to answer and gopal you
can step in and add uh
you know what you're saying so in terms
of the first question on the credit link
business
uh so obviously icc bank contributes a
large part of the credit link business
for us particularly the benefit piece
um if i look at the credit link business
in aggregate that's roughly about
last year was roughly about seven
percent of our of our business
uh as we speak for the q3 uh given the
fact that bank uh
uh took a call to focus on corporates
that's come down to shade lower than
three percent of our business so it's
been a
pretty sharp reduction uh now what can
happen in the next uh you know year
uh so as at this point in time the bank
has clearly said that
they want to continue to focus on their
core business because
in essence they're coming out of uh you
know the slowdown and the mortgage
business in the past
and they're wanting to ramp up that
business
and uh you know what they've told us is
that they will obviously
re-assess this approach once things
stabilize
so we are reasonably hopeful that this
is something that we will
get to see uh in the next year uh coming
back
but if you look at just the uh amount of
business the bank does
for us on the benefit size relative to
the total business that we write
the bank contributes uh a bulk of the
benefit business
we also get a lot of benefit business
from the uh other
non-bank non-icc bank bank insurance
partners nba's hfcs and other banks
that segment you know for this quarter
has actually seen a growth over last
year roughly
13 14 and it's beginning to pick up so
uh
we are reasonably hopeful that that
segment will now uh start picking up but
of course can't replace the bank
given the sheer size of the two uh
earpieces
now as i said so next year is one is we
we are uh we are reasonably uh you know
hopeful that the bank will
uh you know review its uh reassess its
approach
uh but the more important thing is you
know next year with if you had
a partner then by the way we are adding
partners last year we added a couple of
banker partners
this year we've added uh you know one
more partner which has
we believe reasonable potential and once
the integration happened whatever
happens
in terms of the bank of partners that we
will get obviously all of that will
uh you know uh compensate for any losses
if
if at all it happens your second
question was on motor
um you see uh in motor again you
i'll repeat what i said one of the
advantage one of the uh calls that we
took in the beginning of the year was
that
we will uh you know not take the full
benefit in the first
quarter of the frequency losses we will
uh you know reduction in frequency
and we will you know average it out over
the year
and if you see some some of the other
players in the market had a very sharp
reduction in
uh you know let's say only north ratios
in the first quarter in the first half
for us it was reasonably uh kind of
evened out
because we just wanted to be more
conservative and we believe as i said
that's the right approach
in terms of sourcing so it's in a sense
a kind of a even out
you know loss ratio that you're seeing
in terms of sourcing
you know what we see incrementally in
the business that we are writing
and as you know we have a predicted loss
issue when you write and write a
business
uh we are in a sense back to the
pre-covert situation
if you remember we were saying uh you
know pre-lockdown that the motor od
business is
reached a level where the combine for
the industry is probably 110 because the
sourcing costs and the
loss ratios were pretty elevated because
of
you know hyper competition uh and we
were saying
if you remember q3 of last year and q4
of last year we are saying
we need to see some price increase and
we are beginning to see those
conversations
that were happening that obviously
stopped when the pandemic
lockdown happened as we speak today we
are in the same
boat in the sense that you know because
now the frequencies are back to
pre-covert levels
uh you know people are using their cars
as much as in the past
so we clearly need to see some price
corrections in the
in the in the business and from our
perspective what we've already started
doing this quarter
is actually start pushing the system on
some price increases
uh and you know we are hopefully hopeful
that the market will also move with us
uh because at this level on an
incremental basis the business is
under severe pressure uh so i hope that
uh
you know answers i i was largely
referring to motor tp the last issue is
being
i'm talking about motor only i was there
but what's my question
i'm sorry but my question was more more
towards motor third party where the loss
ratios have become
like 65 66 percentage uh so so
there seems to be very low number
compared to our historical past
so whether whether that number is
sustainable or not because because
uh uh we just wanted to understand is it
easy because of the reserve reviews or
is it because of
low plane intimidation uh because
because we usually used to operate in
the range of eighties
and and maybe before in five 18 kind of
a period around 90
a percent loss ratio so this 65 66
percentage kind of a number
is more sustainable number or or we are
still we are seeing the reserve release
benefit or low claim intimidation
benefit and that's why we are seeing
these kind of a very
great good set of numbers in multi-tippy
location so on moto tp you should
look at an annual number as we've always
said there could be periods where for a
quarter we could
you know as you know every quarter they
actually looks at the
data and takes a call on the adequacy of
reserve so there could be some
fluctuation on a quarterly basis you
should look at the annualized number
but to answer your question we believe
there's been definitely a positive in
terms of frequency drops we've seen that
across our portfolios we've also seen
some releases uh
you know in this quarter because of the
uh you know conservative
practices of reserving that we've had
but what we're also doing
incrementally is whenever we look at
reserving for the new book that we write
for the future
we create uh you know again a
conservative buffer
uh you know margin for adverse deviation
as we call it
and so that practice hasn't changed we
continue to be conservative in terms of
reserving fraud
for the incremental book but we've seen
a bit of benefit on both sides and
that's what we are seeing but i think
you should wait for the whole year
number before we
uh take a full call that's on the tp
side
and you had a third question on i think
on a new
new retail internet so
on the indemnity part i think if you
look at uh in general
if you were to look at particularly uh a
large part of indemnity
gets sold in the context of the industry
classification of retail health
there if you can clearly see the
industry growth in line with what we are
also indicated that
obviously in the initial periods of the
covet situation
there was clearly a heightened awareness
and the need for
one to have some form of health
insurance or the other and that's also
reflective in so far as the overall
growth for the market also so if you
look at quarter one growth of retail
health for the industry was about 24
this number if you see for quarter two
the industry growth on retail health was
almost about 43
and if you see for quarter three the
industry growth on
retail health is down to about 23 so
clearly
in some sense some of the pent up demand
that we had seen
for quarter two to some extent obviously
we have seen
let's say a moderation of the
growth rates in line with what we are
also indicated saying that
the level of incremental growth that we
are seeing particularly in quarter two
we will have to wait and see in terms of
its sustainability and to some extent
what one has already seen uh that
playing off when you look at the overall
industry growth for
uh quarter three sh now in this backdrop
if you look at isis lombard's internet
growth
again in the context of retail for
against the industry of 24 percent our
quarter one growth was about 25 percent
if you look at quarter two the industry
growth was about 42 what i had indicated
40 43 our growth rate was about 35
percent
and for quarter three for us the
indemnity growth rate has been
at about 17 so in line with the
industry trend even we are kind of
experiencing
let's say a relative slow down of the
pent-up demand that we have seen in
quarter two specific
and to that extent obviously the 17
percent growth will have
ah an impact
in so far as both what we see as new
indemnity growth and also the extent of
renewals that one gets to see so largely
the
growth rates have been in line with what
we are saying and also in so far as the
market is concerned so just to add to
what gopal said even if you look at
the month or month number in q3 uh for
october we were higher than the market
growth in november we
relaunched the health product a complete
revamp we had talked about it in in last
quarter
here also and that initially took some
time to stabilize in the market because
new product
training agents etc but december numbers
are
you know has picked up compared to
november and we are almost in line with
the market for december but
in aggregate over the three months we
are slightly below uh the industry so we
are reasonably hopeful that
uh you know that we should be uh
continually doing well in the uh
retail indemnity space
okay yeah that's it for myself thank you
thank you the next question is from the
lion of deepika mundra from jp morgan
please go ahead oh yes good evening sir
and uh thanks for the opportunity
a few questions from my side um last
quarter you had mentioned you took a
price increase in health
uh i think uh your uh your commentary
indicated that even more
only the price is monolith stabilizing
um
and you're typically guided to a 99
percent or combined or 200 combined
ratio would you
would you think that you could finally
see a a meaningful underwriting profile
shift with the
change in pricing cycle uh the second
question is on
uh the pnc business uh if uh have you
renewed any of the reinsurance treaties
in january
and uh is there a great increase which
will further impact cnc
protecting gopal you want to take the
second question
uh yeah so deepika i think uh you are
absolutely right i think uh
the uh pnc business two things one you
have to
uh one you have to be mindful of the
fact that uh
the growth rates what you are seeing
particularly in the pnc segment of which
a large contributor happens to be the
fire part of the business
the industry has done exceedingly well
on
primarily driven by the rate change that
we had seen on two occasions in the last
12 months or so so hence to that extent
when you
now look at renewals that will that to
some extent happens in january 1
and predominantly bulk of the renewals
that will happen from april 1 onwards
you will have to kind of factor in for
some kind of a normalization of growth
rate
in so far as the fire segment is
concerned so that's one in so far as
revenues are concerned to your point on
the reinsurance
uh there this this is quarter four is a
period where bulk of the
discussion starts to happen in so far as
renewals are concerned
and hopefully towards the later part of
the quarter is where
most of our reinsurances will get
stitched in
because for us april 1 happens to be a
predominantly very large
big day for us and hence as i said in
quarter in
the later part of quarter four is where
most of the renewals will happen in the
context of reinsurance
having said that i think what we have
what we are seeing
as uh initial uh experiences in so far
as discussion with researchers are
concerned
uh again it's purely a function of what
kind of portfolio experience are you
exhibiting with the insurance partners
to that extent i think given that we
have been able to stay disciplined with
our overall operating outcomes of
combined within that hundred percent
threshold
we believe again in terms of renewing
the terms with reinsurers are concerned
we should not see any significant
but of course
there will obviously some element of to
some extent of
a price hardening that one would expect
but
we are not expecting any anything
significant given the portfolio
experience
that isis alumni has been able to
exhibit uh relative to the quality of
the book that we have deleted
and just to add to what gopal said if
you see you know january 1
uh renewals in the global market and
what's been happening in the asian
market
you know what was expected maybe five
six months back in terms of
significantly high significant hardening
of reinsurance rates
that hasn't played through in asia and
even within that
the treaties that have been performing
well
haven't seen tremendous uh you know rate
increases so we remain reasonably
uh you know optimistic about the uh you
know discussion of the reinsurance even
if there's some
increase it may not be material coming
back to your first question deepika so i
think this is something that we've been
saying right that
if structurally the interest rate uh of
environment of the country comes down
and stays down
you know honestly we have always been
saying that we don't
believe that that may happen but if it
happens um
you know the industry will be forced to
become a lot more disciplined
on combined uh from i was referring more
to a short term term
phenomenon that if you remember last
year also we were saying that motorola
prices have to increase
and then we had the pandemic and you
know lockdown and hence there was
really no need for that but i think
again today
there is probably the same pressure that
the industry would be facing
at least we are you know taking some
lead in trying to
push the pricing where we believe it's
uh reasonable
uh you know ask and we'll see how it
plays through
in this quarter we are reasonably
hopeful that we'll be able to make some
uh headway
okay that's thank you
thank you the next question is from the
line of viruses
from iifl please go ahead yeah thanks
for the opportunity am i clear i mean
you know what i mean
yeah okay okay um so
a couple of questions one on uh you know
motor i think you know in the in your
initial remarks you were talking about
some business acquisition related
expenses i'm sorry i missed a major part
of that um you know what exactly has
happened on the
opex ratio for us given that uh there's
almost a 35
q increase in both topics as well as
uh as well as on the commission site
just wanted to you know again understand
i think you were talking about the
acquisition of uh the transaction that
we announced i think but anyway you can
explain that
yeah so i think in general uh rishi what
effectively has happened is
i think you are referring to the
increase in the overall cost
so what we were indicating was whenever
growth starts to come back
as what we have seen in quarter three uh
we have been able to see an overall
gross premium growth of almost about 9.2
percent within that if you would have
seen motor growth has been
quite reasonable at almost about 14
growth so whenever growth starts to come
back there is always
uh an impact of the upfronting of
acquisition cost that place through the
p
l immediately whereas the benefit in the
form of earned premium is something that
will play through uh over the uh
policy period and that's evident when
you look at for example
the uh net return premium growth rates
for quarter three
that number is about 20 so so the
benefit of that
nwp is something that will play through
as the earnings happen
however the cost is something that comes
and hits you upfront
however this largely gets taken care of
so when you look at it from an absolute
number
obviously to that extent the
underwriting number will look a little
adverse
on an absolute basis but when you look
at it in the context of
the expense ratios i think
for example when you look at quarter two
i am talking about both since you
mentioned about both opex plus
commissions put together a quarter to
the opex plus commission ratios was
roughly about
33.9 uh that number if you look at for
quarter three that number is down to
about 32.4 percent
and within that if you look at the opex
ratios the operax ratios for
quarter two was 27.3 and quarter three
that number is about 25.4
and this even if you see vis-a-vis
quarter three of last year
that number was at 24.7 i'm just talking
about opex ratios number
that was 24.7 visibility 25.4 for
quarter three of this year
so hence to that extent i think from a
combined perspective
the impact of upfronting of expenses
gets taken care of
however from an absolute underwriting
outcome you then
because of the upfronting of cost you
get to see the underwriting results to
be little uh adverse
and just to add to one more point to
open what gopal said you know when you
look at qoq
q3 is a very big period for uh for motor
compared to q2 right and and if you see
the growth rate for
q3 over q3 last year and growth rate of
q2 over
q2 last year we actually had an even
higher growth in q3
so on both accounts there would be an
increase and the other point that gopal
i think made on the
opening call was the fact that uh you
know the acquisition that we
announced bharti axa uh that cost has
been uh you know
absorbed in the nine months yeah that
number is about 36 crores
in the p l of the nine months okay
um and so you know so it's fair to
assume that uh you know if the growth
rate numbers stabilize at the current
level then
you know operates as a percentage will
continue to drop
for the next three quarters as you know
incrementally premiums continue to get
recognized but of course costs have
already been
uh incurred for or come through the pms
so far is combined if we slow down
yes related to any quarter whenever we
slow down that will have an impact
you'll see that yeah okay and secondly
can you give us some quantum
you know uh taking fi 20 as a as a base
year
in terms of how much of the benefit
business
uh did we do in fi-2 from iclc bank
and accordingly the impact on on
combined ratio
maybe on an overall equity perspective
gopal you want to answer that yeah
so effectively i think uh rishi what we
had indicated was uh
as vargo mentioned obviously uh bank is
a key
uh distribution partner for us uh in so
far as
sourcing of businesses is concerned uh
and roughly if you look at the overall
contribution that the bank did
in so far as uh premiums are concerned
for fi 2020
roughly bank contributed so again i'm
talking about the overall contribution
of all credit link businesses
whether it is integrity and benefit put
together
that number roughly constituted about 7
percent of the total
gross direct premium income of the
company that's for fi 2020
and in line with what we have been
indicating if you look at for the
current nine months
obviously uh it's driven by two factors
the even to that extent the levels of uh
disbursements have also been lower and
bank specifically
uh also has been a a key factor to a
key factor to it uh and this number of
seven point
one percent that have kind of uh uh
indicated
uh that that's for the fi 2020 if you
look at for
the nine month period the contribution
of
again the total credit linked policies
uh
uh through all channels put together
that number is about two point nine
percent of the gross direct premium
income that we have written for the nine
months so this number issues for all the
bank assurance business ics bank and
others
the 7.1 has gone to 2.9 percent uh and
you know within the the uh you know bank
and non-bank
uh bank uh all you know should be 75 75
would be bank yeah okay and one last
question on the regulatory side so
a couple of things one is that uh you
know has the uh
you know the the rule around uh uh
claim uh intimidation for six months has
that been notified and when do we start
expecting that
you know to play out for the next year
or 12 months hint
on our you know leverage and other
aspects of the
pnl and secondly there is some
recommendations about you know
introducing a new um you know premium
which is related to traffic violations
do you think that is something which
would potentially pass and pose a
upside risk i mean how does that uh
playing out
what do you think about this one the
claims i don't see
it to be a big uh impact for us because
anyway you know six months we would have
we would pay most claims
uh within that time frame so we don't
see too much of an impact financially uh
for us
um on the second one this is just a
report that has come from the committee
obviously there is a lot of interest
across all
policy makers in bringing down accidents
on the road and improving role safety
and one of the obvious factors is the
way people drive
uh so you know this is something
you know for which the time had come
whether it will happen in this
in the coming year or not that's
difficult to predict it may not happen
so soon
but it will happen in due course there
will have to be a lot of
uh you know system uh in a sense uh
or data exchange that we'll have to do
uh as an industry and with the
you know other the police systems to be
able to do this that
you know seamlessly but it will happen
in due course may not happen
uh in a matter of six months of course
but will happen in due course is our
sense
thank you so much and i think we didn't
answer your question
on the combined impact on the credit
link just to complete that
i think what we've been also saying is
that roughly about seven seven and a
half percent of our profit comes from
this
business so that has had an impact in
this quarter uh
and it has an impact of over 1.3 to 1.7
percent of our
on our combined the credit linked health
business
that we write all day thank you
thank you the next question is from the
line of nades chain
uh thanks for the opportunity sir
firstly uh
if i look at the motor segment we have
gained the significant
market share in nine months and this
quarter uh
so what has proven that whether we have
gained market share in the new segment
or it's used
or with any particular two-wheeler uh
four-wheeler and uh
uh which segment we have gained market
share and secondly that
we are talking about that incrementally
the
last show in this segment has reached uh
pre-covered levels and probably the
incremental combined ratio for industry
motor segment is around 110
so in this environment uh is it prudent
to gain
yeah so i think there's let me answer
the second one uh and then i'll ask
sanjeev to answer the first question
uh you know that's a very very excellent
question this is you know in terms of
when to grow market share um
and as you know we are traditionally
uh if i can call it counter cyclical we
are counter cyclical
and uh you know and our focus on gaining
market share in the first six months and
maybe first seven eight months was very
very high
uh as we speak maybe from the month of
december we've
uh turned a bit more cautious on the
motor segment
again becoming a lot more selective
based on what we believe
in terms of the future loss ratio rather
than the loss ratio that we've seen the
last
uh you know maybe seven eight months so
we are
making those adjustments absolutely
correct but sanji we want to take the
first question on where we've grown in
the in the
you know seven eight months that we've
done but i think we uh
we throw on a quarter three number if
you look at it we would have grown in
private car two-wheeler as well as
commercial vehicle
uh clearly our growth has been
excessively driven on
has been almost 33 percent on the
commercial vehicle site
but that being said we i think in a way
what bhagava also mentioned that we will
continue
to see where the opportunity lies and we
will keep growing in those particular
segments
but if you see in terms of the
contribution of new
to the overall book so we used to be
almost 33 percent thereabout it's gone
down to almost 29
we've also gone back to our efficiency
in terms of using also ninja which we
had
acquired last in october so we have got
our attention the quality of retention
that we are able to do all of that has
gone about in terms of driving
our growth in the previous nine months
but our approach
primarily remain tactical as to where we
see an opportunity if we see
something bordering on levels which
don't make sense at the portfolio level
for us we would
feel free to you know uh withdraw from
it and we've done that to some extent in
some of the two in the markets also
in the last nine months because we felt
that it was not
making economic sense for us as a
company to get in so we would
that's the problem overall approach that
we will drive and we felt that in
commercial vehicles there was a good
opportunity available we have gone and
grown that
yeah just to give you uh you know the
breakup of
q3 and nine months for new world uh q3
the last quarter was about 33.66
for nine months was about 30 70 that
sanjeev talked about
thank you before we take the next
question a reminder to participants to
please limit your questions to two per
participant
the next question is from the line of
pratik podar from nepal india asset
management
please go ahead yeah hi sir i just
wanted to check
when you talk about growth in relation
to upfront cost that was there in the
base also right so still we are seeing
that the
increase in costs are outstripping
increase in nwp growth
and also in relation to this uh the
employee cost seems to be flat y so
what's going over there is that this
work from home policy tells the digital
initiatives that's question number one
second is on question number two the
question number two was i'm a bit
puzzled as to you know when you say that
icsa bank is focusing on core i thought
core was also about selling
uh ancillary products was to generate
roe because it's
are we accreted and does that mean that
the icc bank has also stopped selling
sme products uh
such as fire health on the sme side and
lastly so your thoughts on the
third party high x uh which didn't
happen in fi-21 uh will they happen i
mean uh
are you reasonably confident or is there
some indication that
they might happen in fi-22 so these
things
yeah so uh let me the first question
i'll
ask gopal to answer in terms of the
accounting and the impact
uh and the employee cost etc operating
cost uh on the second
no the bank is selling all the other
products so all branch linked
you know independently policies that we
sell to retail customers the sme
business
they're continuing to do that i think
the focus that we talked about for the
bank probably was more on the mortgage
side
and that's where these attachment
policies were the credit link policies
were sold
so that's a segment that they've said
that they want to focus on scaling that
business up
and it's probably they see it as an
opportunity at this point in time and
you know maybe coming from
low numbers in the first half so no the
sme and the other businesses are
continuing with the bank uh
you know with uh you know with relation
to
your third question um sorry i just
missed it
my sense is that look as an industry we
we believe we deserve a tp hype because
last year we didn't get it
uh so we are optimistic that we'll uh
get a hike
uh in the coming year normally we've
always seen tp hikes every single year
so there should be there's no reason why
we didn't we shouldn't get it
this year particularly given the fact
that that last year we didn't uh
get one uh you know there will always
remain a concern about the economic
growth and whether any concern on
you know price increase affecting growth
which in reality there isn't in this
case but
uh but on balance we remain very
optimistic that we'll get a
increase on first april
so on the first point uh i think uh in
what in line with what we have been
saying um obviously
uh uh the market has also been equally
quite competitive and so far as
intensity is concerned and therefore to
that extent uh that will also be a
factor in so far as
acquisition costs are concerned and
which is what i kind of indicated
whenever kind of
growth obviously comes back to that
extent you will have to see it in the
context of
what cost you are required to incur for
sourcing the business and
correspondingly what is the
loss ratio that you are exhibiting on
the overall portfolio and thereby take a
call with respect to the combined issues
that you want to operate at
and that's the reason if you look at it
from an expense ratio standpoint
on a if you look at it on a sequential
basis
both operating expenses plus acquisition
cost put together
the numbers for quarter two was roughly
about thirty three point nine percent
however this number when you look at it
for
uh quarter three uh that number is at
about thirty two point
uh four percent so obviously uh the cost
that you have incurred will get
expressed out immediately
the benefit is something that we play
through over the next
per term of the policy period uh on the
employee cost i think the costs are more
or less remained the same because we
i think clearly the focus for us is to
derive significant
efficiency based on the operating model
and the point that you made is
absolutely right obviously the operating
model is the key factor
and we have not and we are kind of
largely making
additions to people particularly in area
where we want to continue to make
investments therein
otherwise in the rest of the rest of the
functions obviously we want to kind of
realize
both productivity improvement as well as
efficiencies in the overall
cost and that's the reason why you get
to see that number on a sequential basis
remaining more or less flat
thank you the next question is from the
line of madhu karlata from hdfc
securities
please go ahead uh kaiser thank you for
taking my question
uh so our uh health claim ratios are
down this quarter
uh and how should we think about this um
were there reserve releases on the
health segment as well
uh this this quarter and on the
investment portfolio can you tell us uh
what is the duration and yield of the
fixed income book
[Music]
so let me take the second question gopal
you can you could
answer the first question so in terms of
the duration the duration of the book
is increased to about 4.05 uh what we
did
during this quarter which is a slight
increase from the duration that we had
as on 30th september uh the call that we
took
in you know early part of this quarter
was uh
that uh the uh
the um
the um short maturity papers was
running at very low credit spreads
and were probably overpriced so we
reduced some of the exposures there and
increased exposure in the
medium-term notes largely
government securities and uh state
development loads i mean you know we
only invest in a few states which we
like in terms of the quality
and uh that has turned out to be a good
trade
because you know coincidentally rba
announced an omo for sdl's later
uh so that's the move that we made we
still believe that you know interest
rates will
you know remain range bound at least for
uh you know couple of quarters at least
uh and we want to kind of be very
watchful about
uh you know positioning our book
appropriately at a time when uh our
views change
um so at this point in time we just
wanted to uh you know shift the book
to slightly longer uh you know duration
because we felt
that the uh the short duration bonds
were overpriced at that point in time
and so the the average yield and then
uh would that also mean that most of the
capital gains
is from equity this quarter no we've had
a mix of
capital gains on as i said you know the
the short duration bonds uh some of the
corporate bonds in the short duration we
exited we had some capital gains there
because as we said we felt it was
overpriced and we shifted to
uh sdl's and some g6 um
overall yield we are uh you know it's
it's ahead of what we've kind of been
talking about that what we need
uh i don't want to give the exact number
but if you look at the realized written
on the portfolio
uh it's running at about uh if i
remember it's about seven point nine
percent if i remember the gopal you can
count
because you know the portfolio is
roughly at about seven seven by
to your point madukar with respect to
the health loss ratios i think if you
look at it on a year-on-year basis
obviously actually you will see an
increase uh from almost about 69.6 to
what 77.3
but uh yes you're right when you look at
it on a sequential basis you get to see
the number kind of going down in quarter
two from about 81.9 percent to about
74.6 percent
this obviously includes uh let's say uh
health personal accident and travel all
put together
within this i think a large part of that
is with respect to health
that health numbers when you look at it
for quarter two the loss ratio for the
overall health book was
about 91 that number if you see for
quarter 3
is at about 88.1 percent so in general
i think what we have seen is in terms of
the approach that we are taking
in so far as reserving for ibnr is
concerned
keeping in mind the fact that there
could be a possibility of claims that
could kind of come in the subsequent
period to that extent i think we did not
necessarily as we have indicated even in
our earlier calls
not to necessarily factor in for the
whole of the benefit in the initial
period but rather
kind of be a little conservative and see
the actual losses kind of playing
through
over the subsequent quarters and hence
when you start to see
numbers between quarters you would get
to see some kind of a reduction in the
overall loss ratio numbers but honestly
as we keep saying quarters may not
necessarily be representative of
what the true experiences is because
there are multiple factors that go into
the
loss ratio numbers an ideal thing will
be to look at more
on a year-on-year basis and ideally on
an annual basis i think that's what we
would kind of largely suggest and there
even on the health numbers you would
actually see when i gave out the numbers
for 69.6 to 77.3
that again included all the three
components of health personal accident
and travel
within that the health loss ratios
actually increased from about 83 percent
to 88
thank you we'll be able to take one last
question
we take the last question from the line
of shivani
from clse india private limited please
go ahead
hi thank you for the opportunity so just
wanted to check on this
my understanding on the commission
absolute number
so given that the retention ratio is
high this quarter it's at around 78.
whenever the retention ratio is high the
net commission number tends to go up
because that commission that you're
earning from
giving it to reinsurers uh sort of goes
down
is my understanding correct on this is
that also one of the factors
uh pushing up the commission number for
the quarter
so retention share is a function of
multiple segments particularly when you
look at
most of the retail lines i think they i
mean in line with what we have spoken
whether you look at motor for example on
the aggregate portfolio
uh this year we have actually seen uh
particularly on motor own damage until
fi 2020 we had a small uh
reinsurance support beyond the five
percent obligatory on the one damage
portfolio till fi to t20
from fi 2021 even that particular
insurance support which were indicated
even at the beginning of the
year's call is something that we have
done away with and hence to that extent
you will get to see an increase in the
overall
retention numbers so that's one and
similarly
i think the more you write
retail businesses i think in what we
have indicated even the retail indemnity
book for us
has done uh uh reasonably well and there
that's again a business where we kind of
retain predominantly
uh 95 percent of the risk leave aside
the five percent obligatory
the one segment where over the last
so many years we have always had a
reinsurance support is with is with
respect to the
retail uh benefit and that in line with
what we have spoken earlier during this
call
that's a segment where we have seen some
bit of challenges in so far as growth is
concerned so hence
a factor of all of this is what is
leading to
an increase in so far as retention
numbers are concerned
and corresponding to that is where your
net commission
numbers could undergo a change but
that's again purely a function of
what businesses do you write so for
example motor
quarter three we have kind of written we
have grown by almost 14
so that obviously will have and there
there is not so much of reinsurance
support as i explained
it will be purely an increase in
acquisition cost
and similarly on health individually
whatever business that we source
again will be a very high retention
portfolio
but in so far as the cost of sourcing is
concerned that effectively comes as a
part of your net commission numbers so
you have to look at it in the context of
which lines of businesses have grown
what is the retention corresponding to
each of those
as i said for motor predominantly 95 on
the net health indemnity again
predominantly 95
on the net but the cost of sourcing is
something that comes as a part of your
net commission numbers
and just to add to what google explained
so the one retail business that we
traditionally have been reinsuring
is the discrediting business
which uh this quarter has seen a
tremendous drop so
even for that uh the insurance
commission uh
get has dropped understood that's very
helpful thank you
thank you very much we'll take that as
the last question
i would now like to hand the conference
back to mr bhargavas gupta for closing
comments
so just thank you everyone it's been a
late evening
a call that we are doing thank you for
joining us
stay well stay safe thank you thank you
so much
thank you very much on behalf of icici
lombard general insurance company
limited
that concludes this conference thank you
for joining us ladies and gentlemen
you may now disconnect your lines
you